# Mu Yang 楊慕

RESEARCH ASSISTANT · DATA ENGINEER · FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

[] (+886) 920-890-202 | ■ emfomy@gmail.com | 🛪 muyang.pro | 🗣 Taipei, Taiwan | 🗘 emfomy | 🗣 emfomy | in emfomy

# Summary.

A data engineer and full-stack developer with a research background in both computer science and applied mathematics domains. Skilled in frontend web design, deep learning, and parallel computing researches. Experienced in computer cluster formation and maintenance.

## **Education**

**National Taiwan University** 

**National Taiwan University** 

Taipei, Taiwan

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES, SUPERVISED BY PROF. WEICHUNG WANG

Sept. 2015 – June 2017 Taipei, Taiwan

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS

Sept. 2011 – June 2015

# Work Experience \_\_\_

#### **CKIP Lab, Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica**

Taipei, Taiwan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, SUPERVISED BY DR. WEI-YUN MA

July 2017 - Dec. 2020 (expected)

- Developing natural language processing toolkits with Python package and online demo system. # https://ckip.iis.sinica.edu.tw/service/corenlp/
- Devising a syntax parser for E-HowNet (a common-sense knowledge base) and visualization demo system. 

  https://ckip.iis.sinica.edu.tw/service/ehnvis/
- Coordinated with PIXNET Corporation and proposed a novel entity linking method on cosmetic domain with dataset and baselines. Published the research paper "Headword-Oriented Entity Linking: A New Entity Linking Task with Dataset and Baseline" in LREC 2020.
- Proposed a general and flexible framework of word embeddings which outperformed various state-of-the-art models.
   Published the research paper "HWE: Word Embedding with Heterogeneous Features" in IEEE-ICSC 2019.
- Designed and implemented the lab website. # https://ckip.iis.sinica.edu.tw/
- Established the computer clusters with shared file/login system, and online monitor systems.

#### Institute of Applied Mathematical Sciences, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, SUPERVISED BY PROF. WEICHUNG WANG

Sept. 2013 - Aug. 2017

- Developed a parallel randomized singular value decomposition solver, and implemented it for multinode hybrid CPU-GPU systems.
- Published the master thesis "Highly Scalable Parallelism of Integrated Randomized Singular Value Decomposition with Big Data Applications".
- Redesigned and maintained the computer clusters.

#### Thomas J. Watson Research Center, IBM Corporation

Yorktown Heights, NY, U.S.A

INTERNSHIP, SUPERVISED BY DR. I-HSIN CHUNG

July 2015 - Aug. 2015

- Developed a parallel stochastic search algorithm for variable selection problems on hybrid CPU-GPU supercomputer systems.
- Published the research paper "Particle Swarm Stepwise Algorithm (PaSS) on Multicore Hybrid CPU-GPU Clusters" in IEEE-CIT 2016.

#### **Department of Economics, National Taiwan University**

Taipei, Taiwan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, SUPERVISED BY PROF. SEMIN KIM

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2016

• Conducted numerical experiments and assisted in the research paper "Ordinal Versus Cardinal Voting Rules".

### **Honors & Awards**

Mar. 2019 3rd Place, Formosa Grand Challenge (Chinese TOEFL-like listening comprehension QA)

Taipei, Taiwan

 $Feb.\ 2016\ \textbf{Presentation Excellence},\ 7 th\ Taiwan-Japan\ Joint\ Workshop\ for\ Young\ Scholars\ in\ Applied\ Mathematics$ 

Tainan, Taiwan

Fall 2011 **Top 1 Academic Excellence Award,** Department of Mathematics, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

#### Skills

**Programming** Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Assembly

Web Development HTML/CSS/JS, SCSS/SASS, Node.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Bootstrap/BootstrapVue, Vuetify

Tools Unix, Git, Makefile, CMake, SQL, MATLAB, ŁTĘX

Libraries MPI/OpenMP, LAPACK/MKL/Magma, CUDA, PyTorch/TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn

**Interests** Piano, Singing

Language Chinese (Native), English (Fluent, TOEFL 96/120)

November 2, 2020 Mu Yang · Résumé Page 1 of 1